Asad Farooq Qureshi, MBA

Engineer | MBA | Marketing Professional

+92-304-9009056 | gureshi.asadfarooq@gmail.com | LinkedIn | asadfarooqgureshi.com

Professional Summary

With 5 years of professional experience, I specialize in Digital and Social Media Marketing, GenAI, Marketing Analytics, and Revenue Management. Having worked with international and local clients, I bring a versatile skill set to the table. Right now, I am continually learning about new AI technologies and exploring how they can be integrated into marketing practices and processes to enhance efficiency, streamline operations, and maximize profitability.

Areas of Expertise

- Social Media Marketing
- HubSpot Automation
- WordPress Development
- Google Analytics
- Meta Business Suite
- Data Analysis
- GenAl
- Copywriting
- Project Management

Experience

Marketing Manager - The Rae Team - USA (Remote)

<u>Jan 2024 – May 2024</u>

- Leading all marketing endeavors for "The Rae Team", distinguished realtors in the US, covering social media, website management, paid ads, SF and LF video production, and live webinars hosting.
- Innovatively integrating GenAl into our marketing approach, enhancing efficiency, saving resources, and maximizing impact, distinguishing "The Rae Team" in the competitive real estate market.
- I used the latest AI technology to create **AI avatars** for The Rae Team members.
- This enabled me to create a lot of content without requiring The Rae Team members to be present for
 recording the videos all the time. It saved a lot of time, effort, resources, and money while increasing
 efficiency. As a result, we were able to upload multiple posts a day, significantly boosting the number of
 videos produced each week.

Marketing Executive - Ascendant - Islamabad

Revenue and Distribution Executive

<u>Jun 2023 – Nov 2023</u>

- Due to my strong analytical and data analysis skills, I assumed additional responsibilities within the distribution and revenue management department. In this role, I implemented pricing and promotions strategies, leveraging analytics to drive well informed and data driven decision-making.
- Implemented revenue management practices, elevating property scores of 50%-60% to over 90% on top international OTAs like Booking.com and Agoda, and also **recovered \$40,000 from Expedia**.
- Leveraged data from diverse sources, including Zoho CRM, BookingWhizz, and ERP systems, to craft and execute targeted marketing campaigns across 20+ international and domestic channels, driving revenue growth and brand visibility.

Social Media Marketing & Analytics Executive

Oct 2022 - Nov 2023

- Managed social media and digital marketing efforts for Ascendant and Roomph, driving strategic initiatives to boost brand presence and engagement across various online platforms.
- Led comprehensive data analysis for Pearl-Continental Hotels' mobile app, utilizing tools like Google
 Analytics, Google Firebase, Microsoft Excel, and Microsoft PowerBI to derive actionable insights on user
 behavior, performance metrics, and marketing activities.
- Ensured smooth operations and facilitated effective communication with 20+ international and domestic channels, nurturing strong working relationships with key partners.

- Conducted research on CdZnTe thin-film deposition techniques and defect mapping of CdTe solar cells using Q-DLTS, contributing to published research papers.
- Investigated graphene optical behavior and studied metal contact characteristics on InGaAsP, while developing supercapacitors and a low-cost nano-ammeter.

Marketing and HR Specialist - Youth Impact - Islamabad

Apr 2017 - Dec 2018

- Led public relations, digital marketing, and social media initiatives at Youth Impact, orchestrating promotional campaigns including early bird discounts, countdowns, and special offers to drive participation at Markhor, Pakistan's premier wilderness-based leadership conference.
- Managed human resources and coordinated a diverse team of over 80 members at Youth Impact, overseeing recruitment, evaluations, and internship programs to optimize organizational efficiency and effectiveness.

Professional Certificates

1. Fundamentals of Digital Marketing

Google

2. Ask Questions to Make Data-Driven Decisions

Google

3. Foundations: Data, Data, Everywhere4. The Fundamentals of Revenue Management

Google ESSEC Business School

5. The Fundamentals of Hotel Distribution

ESSEC Business School

When I entered the hospitality industry, I pursued additional education by completing professional certificates in hotel distribution, revenue management, and data analytics. This initiative reflects my commitment to continuous learning and enhancing my skills to excel in my career.

By investing in ongoing education, I ensure readiness to tackle challenges and deliver exceptional results in my career.

Education

Master of Business Administration, MBA (Marketing) – FAST NUCES, Islamabad Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering, BS-EE (Embedded Systems) – FAST NUCES, Islamabad

Extra-Curricular Activities & Interests

- I love traveling, always eager to discover new destinations and meet new people.
- Reading is a big part of my life I'm into a wide range of genres.
- Staying fit and healthy is important to me, so I keep active with sports like basketball, football, and table tennis and regularly go on hikes in the winter season.
- I had a blast playing basketball for my university team and competing in city-wide tournaments.
- During my time at the university's career service office, I organized engaging events like alumni homecoming, job fairs, and educational seminars.